# **Emmanuel Senft**

## Curriculum Vitae

#### CONTACT

Address Plymouth University, A216 Portland Square

Drake Circus, Plymouth, PL4 8AA

United Kingdom

Email emmanuel.senft@plymouth.ac.uk

Phone +44 (0)7751 689105

Website https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/index.html

Scholar https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=Yw1tGf4AAAAJ&hl=en

#### RESEARCH STATEMENT

Robots I research and develop Interactive Machine Learning systems for robots interacting Learning to socially with humans. My current research is centred around SPARC (Supervised Interact Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies), a framework of interaction allowing humans to teach robots to interact with humans in the real world. My research lies at the intersection between social Human-Robot Interaction, Interactive Machine Learning and Learning from Demonstrations.

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2014-2018 PhD, Plymouth University, Plymouth, UK, Obtained in November 2018. Supervisory team: Professor Tony Belpaeme, Dr. Paul Baxter and Dr Séverin Lemaignan
- 2011–2013 Master of Science in Robotic and Autonomous Systems, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.5/6. With Minor in Area and Cultural Studies.
- 2008–2011 Bachelor of Science in Microengineering, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.29/6.

## PHD THESIS

Title Teaching Robots Social Autonomy From In Situ Human Supervision

link https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/ESThesis.pdf

#### MASTER THESIS

Title Hybrid Optimisation with Roombots (Maximum possible grade obtained: 6/6)

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 2018 The PInSoRo Dataset: Supporting the Data-Driven Study of Child-Child and Child-Robot Social Dynamics S. Lemaignan, C. Edmunds, E. Senft, T. Belpaeme PLOS ONE, 2018.
- 2017 Supervised Autonomy for Online Learning in Human-Robot Interaction E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme Pattern Recognition Letters, 2017.
  - How to Build a Supervised Autonomous System for Robot-Enhanced Therapy for Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder P.G. Esteban, ..., E. Senft, ..., T.Ziemke Paladyn, Journal of Behavioral Robotics. De Gruyter Open, 2017.
- 2016 From Characterising Three Years of HRI to Methodology and Reporting Recommendations P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, E. Senft, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (alt.HRI) (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
  - **Social Robot Tutoring for Child Second Language Learning** J. Kennedy, P. Baxter, **E. Senft** and T. Belpaeme Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
- 2015 SPARC: Supervised Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy and T. Belpaeme. Proc. 7th International Conference of Social Robotics (ICSR), Paris, France, October 2015.
- Complete list https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/publication.html with pdf

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2019 **PC Member**, International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS).
- 2017-2018 PC Chair, AAAI Fall Symposium on AI for HRI (AI-HRI).
- since 2015 **Reviewer**, Scientific Reports, JIST, SORO, ICRA, MECH, HAI, JHRI, IS, HRI, ICSR, HUMANOID, RO-MAN....
- 2015-2017 **Demonstrator**, *ROCO 318 Mobile and Humanoid Robots*, Plymouth University, UK.
  - Leading practical work on bipedal gait design and control for 3rd year students.
  - 2014 **Construction Assistant**, *Biorobotic Lab*, *EPFL*, Lausanne, Switzerland, Two months.
    - Development of a controller using a camera and an IMU as inputs to allow autonomous docking on a passive grid using Roombots.
- 2012–2013 **Internship**, *EPFL+ECAL Lab*, Lausanne, Switzerland, Four months.

  Development of a driver for a multitouch tactile wall for a permanent interactive installation at the Red Cross Museum, Geneva, Switzerland.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python, ROS, QML, C++, Machine Learning (Neural Networks and Reinforcement

Learning), Robotics, Nao, Human-Robot Interaction, Study Design, Academic

Writing

Intermediate Solidworks, ProEngineer, MatLab, C, JAVA, Pepper and YARP

Basic Robot Simulator (Webots) and Assembly

## Languages

French Mother tongue

English Advanced Conversationally fluent and technical

German Basic Level A2

Italian Elementary Level A1

Mandarin Elementary Level A1

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

2016-2017 **Comittee member**, *Karate-UPSU*, Plymouth University, UK.

Treasurer for the university karate club.

2014-2018 **Member**, A+E, Plymouth University, UK.

Mountaineering, climbing and caving student club.

2014-2018 Member, Karate-UPSU, Plymouth University, UK.

Karate student club.

2010-2013 Comittee member, Jdr-Poly, EPFL.

Association for the promotion of Role Playing Games and Board Games on the campus.

2007-2013 Scout Team Leader, Eclaireuses et Eclaireurs Unionistes de France, Douvaine,

France.

Team management and leadership, organisation of events with 8-12 or 12-16 years old children with legal responsibility, member from 1998 to 2014.

2008-2012 **Member**, *Robopoly*, EPFL.

Robotic Association.